这是二零二四年普通高等学校招生全国统一考试英语科听力部分。该部分分为第一、第二两节。注意。回答听力部分时，请先将答案标在试卷上。听力部分结束前，你将有两分钟的时间将你的答案转涂到答题卡上。现在是听力试音时间。
Hello, hello. I read about your club in the paper today, and I thought I'd phone to
find out a bit more.
Yes, certainly. Well, we're sort of a social club for people from different
countries. It's quite a new club.
We have about 50 members at the moment, but we're growing all the time.
That sounds interesting.
I'm British, actually, and I came to Washington about three months ago.
I'm looking for ways to meet people.
What kinds of events do you organize?
Well, we have social get -togethers and sports events, and we also have language
evenings. Could you tell me something about the language evenings?
Yes. Every day except Thursday, we have a language evening.
People can come and practice their languages, you know, over a drink or something.
We have different languages on different evenings.
Monday, Spanish, Tuesday, Italian, Wednesday, German, and Friday, French.
On Thursday, we usually have a meal in a restaurant for anyone who wants to come.
Well, that sounds great.
I really need to practice my French.
Okay. Well, if you can just give me your name and address, I'll send you the form
and some more information.
If you join now, you can have the first month free.
听到此结束。听力考试正式开始。
Let's of part.
请看听力部分第一节。第一节，听下面五段对话，每段对话后有一个小题。从题中所给的
three A, B, and Read
三个选项中。选出最佳选项。听完每段对话后，你都有十秒钟的时间来回答有关小题和阅读下一小题。每段对话仅读一遍。例如。现在你有五秒钟的时间看试卷上的例题。你将听到以下内容。
Excuse me, can you tell me how much this shirt is?
Yes, it's 9.15.
你将有五秒钟的时间，将正确答案标在试卷上。衬衫的价格为九磅十五便士，所以你选择项，并将其标在试卷上。现在你有五秒钟的时间阅读第一小题的有关内容。
Look, we have time for a hamburger from a fast food restaurant.
Forget that. I know a new restaurant on Maple Street, not far from our company.
Is that okay with you?
Perfect. Hi, Vicki.
I remember our class presentation is on Wednesday, but you said it's on Thursday.
Are you sure?
Oh, sorry. It was a slip of the tongue.
I meant Tuesday for sure.
Alan's Furniture. Can I help you?
Hi, I'm the one who asked about the price of a glass tea tabletop just now.
I'm sorry, I made a mistake.
The size should be 75 cm by 50 cm.
Oh, that'll make a difference in the price.
Hold on and let me find out.
These are our new arrivals.
Every man should own at least one woolen sweater, don't you think?
I agree. Any suggestions?
The one with two pockets sells best this year.
Lightweight and stylish.
Would you like to try it on?
How do you like your school,
Oh, I like it a lot.
And I also like the area.
The nearby recreation center is cool.
Thank you, Mom.
What a relief that happy with your new home.
你'第一节到此结束。第二节，听下面五段对话或独白。每段对话或独白后有几个小题，从题中所给的三个选项中选出最佳选项。听每段对话或独白前，你将有时间阅读。各个小题，每小题五秒钟。听完后，各小题将给出五秒钟的作答时间。每段对话或独白读两遍。听下面。念一段对话，回答第六和第七两个小题。现在你有十秒钟的时间阅读这两个小题。
here. I don't know if I want to go to I don't think I'll do very well there.
Why not? Because I'm not smart.
Yeah, it can be scary.
Did you ever come close to dropping out, Dad?
No, but I worried a lot before I went, because I thought college would be full of
brains. Once I got there, I found out that most of the kids were just like me.
I don't know if I want to go to college.
I don't think I'll do very well there.
Why not? Because I'm not smart.
Yeah, it can be scary.
Did you ever come close to dropping out, Dad?
No, but I worried a lot before I went, because I thought college would be full of
brains. Once I got there, I found out that most of the kids were just like me.
don't know to don't think there.
Chapter Well, we feel that they're singing louder, because they sing in typically
听下面一段对话，回答第八至第。十三个小题。现在你有十五秒钟的时间阅读这三个小题。
noisy places. But when the noise is gone, they sing quieter than they normally do.
So, in other words, birds are like us.
In a noisy bar, for example, people will raise their voices.
Exactly. We know that birds sing quieter on the weekend mornings.
This is because the noise levels are lower than the weekday rush, and that's
probably what's happening now.
Here, I've recorded a call of a songbird.
Listen to see if you can hear the difference.
Hello, listeners. People around the world are reporting that birds are much louder
these days. Now, I've connected with Dr.
Zollinger, and let's hear what she will say.
Well, we feel that they're singing louder, because they sing in typically noisy
places. But when the noise is gone, they sing quieter than they normally do.
So, in other words, birds are like us.
In a noisy bar, for example, people will raise their voices.
Exactly. We know that birds sing quieter on the weekend mornings.
This is because the noise levels are lower than the weekday rush, and that's
probably what's happening now.
Here, I've recorded a call of a songbird.
Listen to see if you can hear the difference.
听下面一段对话，回答第十一至第十三三个小题。现在你有十五秒钟的时间阅读。读这三个小题。
Hi. I don't think we've met before.
I'm Mike. Hi, Mike.
My name is Gina.
Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you, Gina.
Where do you come from?
Well, originally, I'm from Canada, but we moved to Australia when I was about five
years old. Now my parents live in Tokyo.
How about you, Mike?
I was born in Glasgow, and we lived there until I was six.
Then, since my father worked for an international trade company, we moved all over
the place. Oh, yeah?
Where are some of the places you've Most of the time, we lived abroad.
We spent a total of ten years in Japan, Germany, and Korea.
We came back to the UK only two years ago, but I think my parents would prefer to
stay overseas for another twenty years.
Wow. It sounds like you've had an interesting life.
Hi. I don't think we've met before.
I'm Mike. Hi, Mike.
My name is Gina.
Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you, Gina.
Where do you come from?
Well, originally, I'm from Canada, but we moved to Australia when I was about five
years old. Now my parents live in Tokyo.
How about you, Mike?
I was born in Glasgow, and we lived there until I was six.
Then, since my father worked for an international trade company, we moved all over
the place. Oh, yeah?
Where are some of the places you've
Most of the time, we lived abroad.
We spent a total of ten years in Japan, Germany, and Korea.
We came back to the UK only two years ago, but I think my parents would prefer to
stay overseas for another twenty years.
Wow. It sounds like you've had an interesting life.
听下面一段对话，回答第十四至第十六三个小。小题。现在你有十五秒钟的时间阅读这三个小题。
is don't Gina.
you. Good morning.
Welcome the space hero, Mr.
Green, to my studio.
Hello, Maria. Hello, my dear friends.
Well, let's start from the first question I collected from the audience.
Did you have any moments of dizziness since you landed back on the Earth?
The first three days back were pretty tough.
Your body system is all messed up, so you feel dizzy.
It's quite normal, though.
Thanks. Another question.
Would you go for the first manned Mars travel, if you have the chance?
Absolutely. A trip to Mars is hugely exciting.
I'm always ready for it.
know you can watch movies on the space station.
What's your favorite space movie?
Some people asked.
Apollo 13 is probably my top one.
And my sons love Blue Earth.
It was brilliant watching the new movie on board the space station.
Good morning. Welcome the space hero, Mr.
Green, to my studio.
Hello, Maria. Hello, my dear friends.
Well, let's start from the first question I collected from the audience.
Did you have any moments of dizziness since you landed back on the Earth?
The first three days back were pretty tough.
Your body system is all messed up, so you feel dizzy.
It's quite normal, though.
Thanks. Another question.
Would you go for the first manned Mars travel, if you have the chance?
Absolutely. A trip to Mars is hugely exciting.
I'm always ready for it.
I know you can watch movies on the space station.
What's your favorite space movie?
Some people asked.
Apollo 13 is probably my top one.
And my sons love Blue Earth.
It was brilliant watching the new movie on board the space station.
Listen Our next dress -up day will be on Friday, October 28th, and it is our annual
听下面一段独白，回答第十七至第二十四个小题。现在你有二十秒钟的时间阅读这四个小。题。
dress -up day.
On this day, students may dress up in fun clothes, and there will be a march around
the school. Students are reminded not to carry sharp things, such as knives and
swords. And please make sure that you can see and breathe easily if you wear masks.
Parents are invited to watch the but are asked to stand either in front of the
office, near the flagpole, or in the grassy courtyard.
The students will be marching around on the sidewalks, so we do need to keep all
sidewalks clear. Parents and friends may also join in the march if they are dressed
in appropriate clothes,
but if you're just watching, we'd like to ask you to stay in one spot to reduce
traffic jams. Students who do not wish to take part in the event, for religious or
other reasons, should inform their teacher, and they will be allowed to stay in the
office until after the event.
Our next dress -up day will be on Friday, October 28th, and it is our annual dress
-up day. On this day, students may dress up in fun clothes, and there will be a
march around the school.
Students are reminded not to carry sharp things, such as knives and swords.
And please make sure that you can see and breathe easily if you wear masks.
Parents are invited to watch the but are asked to stand either in front of the
office, near the flagpole, or in the grassy courtyard.
The students will be marching around on the sidewalks, so we do need to keep all
sidewalks clear. Parents and friends may also join in the march if they are dressed
in appropriate clothes,
but if you're just watching, we'd like to ask you to stay in one spot to reduce
traffic jams. Students who do not wish to take part in the event, for religious or
other reasons, should inform their teacher, and they will be allowed to stay in the
office until after the event.
第二节到此结束。现在你有两分钟的时间，将试卷上的答案
on Thank you.
转涂到答题卡上。
Thank you. Thank you.
听。力部分到此结束。